<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xml="http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

<H3>Functional Requirements</H3>
	<P></P>

	<P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    1. Ability for participating clinics to access Hepatitis B and C “Case Report” forms online.
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    2. Ability for participating clinics to access Hepatitis B and C “Care” forms online.
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    3. Ability for participating clinics to write data to the demonstration FHIR server.
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    4. Ability for project owners to extract FHIR data from the demonstration server in a format suitable for data visualization or statistical computing tools like “R” for statistical analysis.
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    5. Ability of participating clinics to read their data, including patient demographics, from the demonstration FHIR server.
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    6. Ability to limit the access to authenticated users only. 
  </P>

<P></P>

<P></P>

<H3>Stakeholders</H3>
	
  <P></P>

	<P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    1. Department of Health
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px">  1.a Epidemiology Bureau (EB) </P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px">  1.b Disease Prevention and Control Bureau (DPCB)</P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px">  1.c Knowledge Management and Information Technology Services (KMITS)</P>
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    2. Participating Health Facilities / Clinics
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 2.a Screening, Assessment, and Treatment Facilities (SATF) - Level 1 - 2 Hospitals and Health Centers </P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 2.b End Referral Facility (ERF) - Level 3 Hospitals</P>
  </P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
  3. Specialty Societies - Hepatology Society of the Philippines</P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px">
    4. Epidemiologist
  </P>

<P></P>
<P></P>

<H3>User Stories</H3>
<P></P>
  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px"> 1. Health Facilities / Clinics </P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 1.a As a member of a participating Health Facility, I want to be able to submit patient Hepatitis B and C data to the demonstration FHIR server through electronic form submission.</P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 1.b As a member of a participating Health Facility, I want to be able to read electronic Hepatitis B and C data from the demonstration FHIR server.</P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 1.c As a member of a participating Health Facility, I want to be able to edit Hepatitis B and C data in the demonstration FHIR server.</P>

  <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:40px"> 2. Epidemiologist </P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 2.a As a field epidemiologist, I want to be able to read individual patient Hepatitis B and C data from the demonstration FHIR server. for track and trace purposes.</P>
      <P ALIGN="JUSTIFY" STYLE="margin-left:60px"> 2.b As a research epidemiologist, I want to be able to electronically access anonymized collected form data so that I can do statistical analysis.</P>

<P></P>
<P></P>

</div>
